Hello everyone, welcome to this video.
In this video, we will see how do we
implement the various orchestration
types supported by Azure Agent
Framework. So in the previous video, I
clearly explained what are the
orchestration type and how do we use it.
If you need further information, you can
refer to this particular blog where like
they clearly explained the various
orchestration types. And if you need a
code samples, you can always get it from
Microsoft. So this is the link for that
particular g repo from where you can see
the samples. So now let's go to the
visual studio code and see how do we
implement this. So for this particular
sample what I want to do is that I want
to write a kind of a blog. So I will be
passing some input to the writer. Writer
will be writing some draft and like that
will be passed to the SEO. Then finally
that will be passed to the editor agent
to do the final review and publish the
blog. So input if you see like I will be
passing artificial intelligence in 2026
and finally I will be having some draft
version here. So now go and see the code
sample here. So if you see here I have
three different agent writer SEO editor.
So now let's go and see like what do we
have here. These are all very simple
class- based exeutor. If you see here
the editor agent it is inherited from
the exeutor and it has a single method
called publish content. It takes the uh
string as an input and like it finally
yields the output. Pretty similar. If
you just come over here, if you see the
writer agent, this is again extended
from the executor, it has a single
method and it takes a string and returns
the strings. You can very well replace
the hardcoded values with llm so that it
will mimic the real world execution. But
that is not the whole point here. I'm
just trying to show you what is this
workflow it's all about. So now if I
just come over here I have a workflow
builder. I'm setting this writer as a
executor and like adding the edges from
writer to SEO SEO to editor. So now let
me run the workflow. If you look into
the workflow output our input it's
passed to the writer. The writer's
output pass to the SEO. SEO's output
pass to the editor. Finally we printed
the result here. So this simulates the
sequential workflow. Now let's move
forward and let's talk about conditional
workflow. So if you see here we will be
sending some input and like we will have
some condition based on which we will
execute one portion of the workflow. Say
like this is for a order processing. So
if order it's greater than a certain
value we will apply some discount if not
we do not apply any discount. And
finally we print the uh summary here.
Let's go to the code and see how do we
implement this. So if you see here I
have a parser order. So basically like
we will be sending the JSON as a input
to the workflow. This parser order will
convert the JSON into a uh object called
order. Then in the age we are adding
apply discount with the condition when
the order value is greater than 500.
Then finally we will be sending to
generate summary. There is going to be
another route where like we will not be
applying any discount when the order
total it's less than 500. Then finally
we will be sending the uh summary here.
So if you see here uh we will be
receiving the input here as a JSON
parcel will convert to a object and like
we will see if it is greater than 500 we
will apply then finally to the summary.
Same thing if it is less than 500 it
goes to no discount then finally we will
be printing the summary. With that let's
go ahead and run the flow here. Let me
clear the terminal. So this is going to
be 31st program.
If you look into the output, we are
running two orders. First, we will have
a large order. So this is the order
total. And as you see here, 5 percentage
discounted supplied and this is going to
be the final total. And we are also
running a small order here. This is the
total and like there is going to be no
discount and the final total it will be
the same. So this is how we can use the
conditional flow. So we can also use the
uh switchbased condition here. Time
around what we want to do is that we
will be applying a premium discount. If
the total is greater than 1,000 if it is
between 500 and 1,000 the standard
discount will be applied less than 500
there is no discount. So now let me go
ahead and open the program here. If you
see here same implementation we are
using the parse order that will convert
to a order object. If the total is
greater than 1,000 then we will apply a
premium discount. Uh between 500 and
1,000 we will apply a standard discount.
Uh if not there is no discount here. If
you see here we are using this which
case here. So the this is the first case
this is the second case and this is
going to be the default case. Everything
else will be the same. So with that let
me go and run the program. So if you see
the output we are processing three
different orders. So if I just see here
there is a small order with no discount
and we also have some standard order
wherein like 5%age discount it's applied
and we also have some premium order
wherein like we have 10%age discount and
this is how we can use the switchbased
flows and then we also have some
concurrent flow. So let me expand this a
bit. So if you see here what we want to
do is that we want to search the flight
between Toronto and Bangalore and there
are some n number of providers. We don't
want to go one after another like like
when we say like go and search for the
flight. We should be able to search
across all the providers. Finally all
the results will be sent to the
aggregator. Then finally we will print
the best deal. Right? So this is the
real case uh implementation. So if you
just go here. So here the flow like we
do a start with the search then we uh
create a fan out node in the sense like
basically like from one uh node we will
be sending the input to multiple nodes
like from search we will be sending to
delta and united and like fan in in the
sense like from multiple nodes we will
be sending the output to a single node
in the sense it is going to be the
aggregator. So this is all about using
fan in and fan out. From search we are
fanning out and like from all other
nodes delta and united we are fanning
in. So with that let let me go and run
the program here. Let me clear the
console.
So if you see the output we are you know
actually going to search first. From
search we go to delta united. both of
these will be sending uh the results to
the aggregator and finally aggregator
will be printing the uh you know best
deal for us. So this is how we can use
the concurrent. So basically the idea is
that from one particular node we will be
calling multiple nodes from multiple
nodes we will be combining the result
into a single node that this is how we
implement the concurrent flow. We can
also use the constructor. So the why do
we use the constructor? We already
discussed in our previous video. The
reason is that the constructor or the
class-based implementation has multiple
features. With the constructor, we
should be able to store and retrieve the
information. Right? So, say like the
same [clears throat] person is trying to
get the result for the same date of same
provider. You don't have to go and pull
the information unnecessarily rather
like you can store that information in a
database and then like pull that
information and that is how we can use
the class-based implementation
especially the constructor. So with that
let me go ahead and run this program
also. Let me create the console.
So if you see the output the output it
is going to be the same except that we
are using the constructor based
implementation. If I just come over here
if you look into the constructor right
now like it might not make a lot of
sense but like now you know that you can
very well use the constructor with the
concurrent workflow. Now let's move
forward. So far what we have done is
that we have used executor as a node. So
now in this program what I want to do is
that I want to use the Azure agent as
the node right. So like what I want to
do is that I want to create multiple
agent in Azure and like I wanted to
utilize all of these agent in my
workflow. So let's see how do we do
that. So if I just come over here it
will be the same exactly we will be
creating the uh agents here. So I create
a writer reviewer. I set this uh writer
as a ex starter node and like from
writer we will be going to the reviewer
from reviewer we will be just printing
the final result. So if you just see
here this is all azure a agent right. So
this is not a typical uh executors this
is a azure a agent. So it has some
instructions. So I create all of these.
If you go to the foundry you will see
all these agent. So now we create this
agent in Azure foundry and we will be
using this in our workflow. So now let's
see how does it work. So this is going
to make use of the LLM. So far like we
have used all hardcoded values. Right
now like we are moving away from the
hard-coded values to make use of the
actual LLM. With that let me go and
clear the console here. Now let me go
ahead and run the program. If you see
the output we are asking the LLM to
create a slogan for the electric
vehicle. So create a slogan for the new
electric vehicle right and like this is
what given to us and uh by the writer
agent that is reviewed by the reviewer
agent finally we have the slogan for us
now what I want to do is that I don't
want to directly use the Azure Agent
rather like I wanted to create the Agent
but like that will be used by the
exeutor that's what we are going to see
here. So if you see here I will be
creating a uh executor and this executor
will be using the agent.
Now let's go and see here. So if you
come over here there is a agent called
topic analyzer. And if you see here
within the executor we are creating or
using the existing agent.
Same case I also have a summary agent.
It also does the same thing. If you see
here it will try to identify the
existing agent. If there is existing
agent, it will use it. Otherwise, it
will create one and use it. Now, let me
go ahead and uh run this program. Let me
clear the console here. If you look into
the output, it is going to create
uh two agent here. So, if you see here,
first it create one for the topic
analyzer. So this is the input that we
given uh artificial intelligence and it
also create one more agent for the
summary and based on which it completes
the workflow. Right? So now what we have
done is that we are using the executors
and the executors internally uses the
Azure Agent. Now we are you know making
use of both the features to build our
workflow. We can also modularize the
overall workflow by using something
called subworkflow or teams. So we will
see how do we do that. Before I do that,
let me clear this console here. So if
you look into this, so this is my team
or you know logical group. So this is
called a copyrightiting team underneath
like I have a writer and a reviewer both
will be used if at all you refer
copyriter team. So there is going to be
input given that will be passed to the
copyrightiting agent. Uh this is going
to be a sequential flow this entity
team. So the copyriter will receive this
information reviewer will review and
pass the input to the next node. So
consider this you know entity team as a
kind of a node though it has two agents
within that. Now let's see how do we do
that. So if you just come over here, we
are creating a writer and a reviewer and
we are using a sequential builder and
participants will be both and like build
and we convert that as a team here by
using something called as agent. By
doing that we the sequential flow will
become a single logical group or a team.
Now what we can do is that within our
workflow instead of referring to the
individual uh agents or nodes we can use
this team agent as a starting agent and
like this is going to be the next node.
In this case this is going to finally
print the value but you know in the in
the similar manner you can logically
group your agents to work together. Now
let let me go and run this program.
So if you see the output here, so we are
asking the workflow to create a wireless
uh toaster here. So this is the toaster.
So basically like the input will be
passed to the team agent. Team agent
consist of those two and then finally
the output will be sent to the final uh
terminal. Right? So far what we have
discussed, you can consider this as a
basic feature. Though you can very well
build the very complex workflows using
these features but still these are all
very basic features. Now we will go and
discuss about the advanced features. So
let me clear this console. So first we
will try to understand the difference
between all of these. So if you see here
I have a comparison between handoff
orchestration, group chat orchestration
and the magnetic builder orchestration.
If you understand the difference between
all of these then it will become easier
for you to use it. So firstly we will
get start with the hand of
orchestration. So think of this way this
is a support team the triage person is
the lead uh so user support request will
be given to the triage person. [gasps]
The triage person will be asking one of
the support engineers to you know work
on that. Think of this way like the
incoming request to return that item.
Then the triage agent will be asking the
triage specialist to perform the you
know needed action. Then the person will
respond back to the triage agent saying
that the return is completed. Then if
there is a need to process the refund,
the triage agent will call the refund
agent. The refund agent will respond
back to the triage agent saying that the
refund is processed or whatever is that.
Now the triage agent will see if there
are any pending action needs to be done
on this user request. If so, it will
perform otherwise it will see the action
is completed. You can think of like you
know lead and the subordinate work
together to solve a specific issue. Then
we have this group chart again like here
we will have a lead. The lead will work
with various agents. Say like the uh you
know there is a request to come up with
some sort of a you know brainstorming
idea. So the lead will be asking uh he
who wants to discuss on this first. The
security person will say hey I want to
discuss first then he will provide the
input to the lead. Then the lead you
know will ask the cloud master hey like
do you have any any input? If so he will
share that information. The lead will
consider both the input and if there are
any additional discussion needed then
the lead will orchestrate. So basically
like the lead here perform the
orchestration uh that the individual
agents will perform the specific action
right. So this is more of a
brainstorming ideas where like you want
to discuss about some marketing strategy
or something of that sort you can
consider this a group chart. Then
magnetic is pretty similar to the group
chart except that the lead will come up
with the plan. So even before you know
it goes to the agent various agents
subordinates it will come up with its
own plan and it will get the approval
from a human hey like this is what I'm
planning to do it for this particular
given task are you okay with that if so
then it will execute the plan first it
will say hey like I need to gather this
information from the security then I ask
these information from the cloud master
and combine this result to provide the
output right so so that is what we will
do with the magnetica builder. So slight
difference between the group chart and
the magnetic uh builder. Group chart
it's like more of a democratic way of
doing it. Hey who wants to go first? You
know you have any additional uh input
for me of something of that sort where
the magnetic one. It's a plan based
execution more of a dictator right. So
the manager or the lead will uh decide
what needs to be done. The subordinate
will just execute the task. Now let's go
and see in action. We will begin with
the hand of flow here. So if you see
here the user request will be passed to
the triage agent. The triage agent will
understand what exactly the user it's
asking for. In this case the user it's
asking for a return and refund. So there
are two action needs to be done. So the
triage agent first will make a call to
the return agent to process the return.
Once the return agent respond back to
the triage JSON saying that it's done
that it will call the refund agent for
the refund. Finally, it will print the
result here. So let me go ahead and run
the program here. If you look into the
output, so user is saying hey like uh I
need a help requesting for your
assistant with the following issue. I
need to return the order one because it
is broken and once the return is started
please uh issue the refund. Now uh the
triage agent or the return agent and the
return agent said I have initiated
uh the return and the like a refund
processing uh it's a handed over. Now
the refund process it's saying that the
refund it's initiated. Now triage agent
it's saying that the case it's closed.
Now finally we have the summary like
what has happened the overall summary
it's here. So here exactly it says that
user asked for you know return on refund
and return agent processed refund agent
processed triage it's closed. So this is
how we could use the handout. Now let me
go ahead and open the program here. So
if you look into this particular program
itself it's a pretty simple. So we have
couple of agents created here. So if you
just come over here. [snorts] So we
created some of these agents here using
the Azure uh you know a agent framework.
We created the triage agent, refund
agent, um order agent and return agent
and whatever the agent that you wanted
to have. Now all of these agents are
here. Now we wanted to build the
workflow. So this time around we will be
using handoff builder. uh and like we
say hey these are all the participants
and this is the name of this uh workflow
and like start with the triage agent and
we see that each agent will get these
many terms. So for instance triage agent
can talk three times overall execution
refund order returns can talk two times
uh in the overall execution. So depends
on your need you will be changing number
of times the agents are allowed to
speak.
Now there is we need to have a
termination condition or you know when
when do we stop the workflow right? So
this is when the workflow gets uh
completed. So first of all we say that
number of messages in the overall uh
workflow history that should be more
than zero which means that at least you
have to have one workflow history
conversation history and then like in
the message you need to have this
particular keyword. It should say keys
is closed because like now if you go to
the triage it is clearly seeing that
when all the task are done you need to
close the keys with this particular
keyword. Now the workflow will get that
information and it will see if you know
the final uh history has this particular
keyword in that message. If so like it
it is indication that the workflow is
completed. As simple as that. So now
let's go ahead and talk about the group
orchestration. So if you see here uh so
there is going to be a a moderator or a
tech lead who will work with the
subordinates. So he will ask for input
from both of these guys and like
finalize the summary here. So in this
case let's assume that what we are
trying to do here is that we wanted to
migrate the payment gateway to Azure. we
plan to use the public VM SQL VM to
manage the uh cost right. So now in this
case the the tech lead will be asking
hey like this is the you know input that
we have and we wanted to do a brainstorm
the security agent will say something
and like the tech lead will be asking
the cloud master basically the architect
and like finally uh he will prepare the
overall summary here. So now let me go
ahead and run this program. Now if you
see the output uh this is what we are
asking. So the this is the proposal and
if you just uh scroll up here first the
security pro it's speaking he's saying
something then uh the cloud master it's
a speaking then uh what do we have then
again like the security pros are
speaking
then
then finally we have the uh final
outcome here. So the overall uh proposal
is this and like this is the uh final
outcome here cloud master outcome and
finally like the security pros are
speaking then um the tech lead says that
uh let's proceed with the uh migration
timeline and begin with the
implementation. Thank you for whatever
is that. So now as you see here whenever
you wanted to have a you know uh
discussion between between the agents
then you can variable use this group
chart orchestration.
Now if you look into the code it will be
very simple. So if you see here [gasps]
um so we are saying like we will be
using the group chart orchestration
and this is the lead and these are all
the participants and this is the
termination condition. So this is how we
build the uh group chart orchestration.
Now let's also talk about the magnetic
orchestration. Uh it will be the same uh
sample but like we will be using the
magnetic orchestration. So here like we
will have a lead and like we will have a
participants uh the overall workflow
count like overall number of times the
workflow can run between the agents it's
a six. So what will happen is that when
the input is given the lead will uh come
up with a plan and request for a manual
approval. Once it is approved the lead
will you know call the individual agents
and finalize the output. So if you just
come over here. So this is how we build.
So here instead of a group chat we will
be using the magnetic builder. So if you
see here we are using group chat
builder. Here we are using the magnetic
builder participants and uh you know
manager and maximum counted six. So it's
a global limit not necessarily for the
individual agent but the overall uh
communication between the agents that
includes the lead and any other agent
that participates in this uh workflow.
Then finally uh we will come out of the
you know iteration and print the result.
Let me go ahead and uh clear this
console. Let me run the program.
So if you look into the output it did go
through a lot of iteration. Finally like
this is the outcome that we have. It
says that do not use the blob storage
rather use the SQL to store this
information.
So far in this video we have covered all
the orchestration types using which you
can build a you know basic workflow to a
very complex workflow.
Now in the upcoming video we will be
discussing about the workflow events
based on which you can get the you know
uh human approval. Say you want to do
something before you actually perform
any action you need to get the uh human
approval that is mandatory right? So we
will see in the next video how do we do
that. Uh, thank you for watching.